## Pei-Chen (Lorna) Yen

• ☑ onpillow@gmail.com • ⑥ https://onpillow.github.io/

#### **SUMMARY**

Research Assistant with a B.A. and M.A. in Finance and 6 years of experience in route optimization algorithm design, route planning system development, and industry financial analysis. Excited to tackle real-world problems by developing advanced technology and leveraging analytics. Seeking to advance my education and research experience in computer science/data science with a focus on Artificial Intelligence.

#### RESEARCH AND WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Graduate Research Assistant**

Institute of Statistical Science, Academia Sinica, Taipei, Taiwan

Advisor: Prof. Frederick Kin Hing Phoa

Full Time, Mar 2019 - Present

# • Transfer Technology Invention: The AIoT Integrated Points-to-Route Optimization (AIoT-iPRO) System for Logistics and Delivery Services

Responsibilities and Achievements

- Invent a map-to-network mapping algorithm based on real maps for distance matrix generation.
- Develop a PSO-style route optimization algorithm that focuses on the problems in discrete domains to address the Traveling Salesman Problem.
- Improve the route optimization algorithm performance for real-world applications; current results outperform the ACO method for small-scale TSP problems.
- Prototype the route optimization solution via Flask framework and Docker: Package the algorithm programming, set up user interface, draw routing results via Google Maps API Service, and dockize with Postgres and NginxuWSGI on Ubuntu system.
- Published Transfer Technology Innovation (Docket Number: <u>06T-1090623</u>).
- Transfer Technology Custom Development: Routing system for multi-trucks with time window constraint for a leading food company in Taiwan
  - Define company's routing problem and search related publications on multi-constrained vehicle routing problems.
  - Design a two-stage model for vehicle routing issues with time windows which is based on "Cluster first, Route Optimization second".
  - Build customized scheduling and routing application for additional constraints such as driver work schedules and super customers; provide scheduling results with table and visualization map.

### **Investment Banking Analyst**

Horizon Securities Co., Ltd., Taipei, Taiwan

Responsibilities and Achievements

Full Time, Jul 2014 – Sep 2017

- Conducted analysis and due diligence as a major book-runner for the Uniflex Technology Inc. IPO (TWSE: 3321).
- Analyzed 5+ companies in electronics and cosmetics industries from financial, operational, and industry perspectives to create memorandum for internal committees.
- Worked with associate to develop 30+ presentations and pitch files for client executives and boards for providing financial and strategic advice.
- Advised clients on official documents such as annual reports, prospectuses, and roadshow files.

#### **PUBLICATION**

**Yen, Pei-Chen** and Frederick Kin Hing Phoa (2021). <u>Traveling Salesman Problem via Swarm Intelligence</u>. *Advances in Swarm Intelligence* Springer Volume **12689**, 106-115.

#### **AWARDS**

#### 3rd XBRL Software Design Competition - Investment Ratings System- First prize

Project Designer - EBO Valuation Model Building

Jan 2014 - Jul 2014

- Designed an innovative security selection model with the EBO valuation method based on public information, including all listed companies, and fundamental corporate analysis.
- Grouped all companies into three main industries: financial, construction and general industry to demonstrate various valuations based on different industry characteristics.
- Collaborated cross-functionally with four IT professionals who led the design, integration and deployment of the designed EBO valuation model into the investment rating system.

#### **EDUCATION**

Fu Jen Catholic University

Taipei, Taiwan

Single subject study (Assessed mode), Bachelor's Program in Software Engineering and Digital Innovation Application

• Coursework: C Language

Feb 2021 – June 2021

• **Overall Grade:** 82 /100

**National Taipei University of Technology** 

Taipei, Taiwan

Single subject study (Assessed mode), Department of Electronic Engineering

Sep 2019 – Jan 2020

• Coursework: Discrete Mathematics

• Overall Grade: 98/100

Fu Jen Catholic University

Taipei, Taiwan

Single subject study (Assessed mode), Department of Mathematics

Sep 2017 - Jane 2018

• Coursework: Calculus I, Calculus II, Linear Algebra I, Linear Algebra II, Mathematical Statistics I, Mathematical Statistics II, Probability Theory

• Overall Grade: 86.74/100

**National Sun Yat-sen University** 

Kaohsiung, Taiwan

Master of Business Administration in Finance, Advisor: Prof. Der-ming Lieu

Sep 2012 - Jane 2014

• Coursework: Valuation Methods, Accounting, Security Market Microstructures, Financial Statement Analysis, Mergers and Acquisitions

• Thesis: Empirical Analysis of Big Data Using EBO Model- Application of XBRL Data in Taiwan's Market

• Achievement: First prize in 3<sup>rd</sup> XBRL Software Design Competition - Investment Ratings System

• Overall GPA: 3.84/4.30

#### Fu Jen Catholic University

Taipei, Taiwan

B.Sc. in Business Administration in Finance and International Business

Sep 2007 - Jane 2011

#### • Extracurricular Activities:

- Department Women's Volleyball Team Captain: Led 30 students in volleyball training and intercollegiate competitions.
- Director of Activities Planning, FJU Financial Club: Hosted three financial courses in partnership with financial institutes; prepared and arranged teaching of basic financial knowledge to ~80 members and attendees

#### **REFERENCES**

- Dr. Frederick Kin Hing Phoa (Research Fellow, Institute of Statistical Science. Academia Sinica) fredphoa@stat.sinica.edu.tw
- Dr. Jun-Jie Pan (Assistant Professor, Department of Mathematics, Fu Jen Catholic University) jackpan@math.fju.edu.tw
- Brian Chiou (Vice President, Horizon Securities Co., Ltd.) gstock.chiou@honsec.com.tw